Hello everybody, Andrew Hyde with Ignite Boulder,
wanted to welcome you to this week show
and also introduce Scott Berkun from Ignite Seattle
talking about how to give an Ignite presentation.
It's fantastic.
If you haven't given an Ignite presentation
this is your inspiration to do it.
If you have, this is how to get better. Enjoy!
Ignite is an ongoing series of speedy presentations.
They range from building multi-person pogo sticks
to hacking chocolate.
Any topic the geeks hold dear.
Each speaker gets only five minutes,
and twenty slides that auto-advance every fifteen seconds.
The talk you are about to hear was recorded live
at one of the featured Ignite events around the world.
I think storytelling is everything.
It is everything!
It's the most important thing that we do,
it's the most important thing that we are.
And if you go about thinking about life
in the perspective that storytelling is everything
then doing things like public speaking or writing or talking
or starting a relationship all become a lot simpler.
Storytelling happens to be a universal thing, it is a timeless thing,
it's something we have done as long as we have been a species,
as long as we've been cultures and tribes and governments
we've been storytellers.
And in effect we align ourselves,
the people we bond with, we have shared stories,
that we often tell again and again with each other.
So storytelling is something we all do all the time,
and we are all good at it.
Any community you're in, any club you join,
any team you root for, there's a set of stories you all share.
So when it comes to doing an Ignite talk,
you guys already have stories
and you are already good at telling them,
because that's why you are alive.
Now, when it comes to doing a talk like this, do in this format
you have to be a little bit more concise
in the kinds of stories you tell.
There's three piles of stories to think about.
The first is what you love, what gets you excited.
Now I know for a fact that all of you
did not commit suicide today. You're here.
Why?
What is it that gets you up in the morning,
what gets you going?
On the other end the spectrum there's what you hate,
what makes you angry.
What would you remove from the world if you could?
Also a place for passion!
You can be passionate about what you hate.
Because in fact if you think about enough of
what you hate and flip it over
you probably have something you should be loving more.
It's a trick involved what you love and what you hate.
The third pile of stuff is what you good at.
What have you been doing for five years or ten years
and you finally have some kind of insight
that you wish someone have told you when you started.
That's money, that so powerful,
that's the most important powerful kinda story
you can tell in a crazy format like this.
And if you have none of these three things,
then your job is a metastory.
You need to do things outside of this format
that will give you opportunities to tell stories about.
And if you fail that, then you get a metastory
about the story how you tried to find
a story to tell but you failed.
That's also a story.
Now.
When it comes to this format people get freaked out about
"i got to tell my story up on stage"
and now there's a whole of dynamic of public speaking
What you should know, there's lots of famous public speakers
that are actually lousy speakers.
People like Cicero, Moses, and this guy, Lincoln.
They're probably actually not very pleasant to listen to.
Its stutters, high-pitched voices,
but what they said was interesting,
they told stories that they refined
they made really clear where their points were.
so people paid more attention of the ideas
and how it's actually said,
which is true today.
And in fact, in fact the other thing be worry
about is the time limit.
The Gettysburg Address is only about two minutes long to read.
You could do two Gettysburg Addresses in one Ignite.
So you have no worries about how long...
"Yo, I cannot fit into..." Yes you can, you can fit it in.
Now the other fear people have has to do with the fact
that the slides move on their own.
There's this Grim Reaper looming overhead,
and every moment it's gonna come like a Terminator
it's gonna knock me into the next thing.
People are terrified about this.
I happen to think it's kind of funny.
I think it's kind of funny in the same way
we worry about things that we can't control.
You have two choices for things you can't control.
You can be paranoid about them, deny them,
or you can revel in them.
And i think it's a perfect format,
you guys know know it's coming,
it's part of the entertainment.
They're all gonna expect to have happen,
and we can make it a joyful experience coming from it, right?
You guys gonna support me if I screw up this slide?
Right? You guys are with me? Right, thank you, alright.
So Ignite audiences happens to be some of
the best audience to speak to
'coz you guys are on my side. You might be
drunk and that may help a little bit,
but you're on my side, you'll back me
if I make a mistake.
So if you wanna try out public speaking
you gonna get good, positive audiences in this environment.
Now the last thing, this is the more practical portion of
my five minutes: how to use time.
It's a philosophical question, but a
practical question for these five minutes.
You only have time to say four or five things,
so, you'll wanna be really careful what they are.
You can't fit that much more into five minutes.
So think about that before you get started.
The second thing is that you'll gonna lose your
first slide and your last slide.
Due to applause, people throwing things at you,
your introduction, you gonna blow those.
So you gonna practice and plan for having
less time than even the twenty slides that you get.
Now the last thing is a little trickier.
People's get up here and they go into full-speed mode,
they're talking like auctioneers on crack.
Going really fast.
You don't have to do that if you don't want to.
So look into the upper right hand corner of this slide.
In a second you'll see a little mark appear,
a little cigarett burn mark
I've now have put the same image
on two consecutive slides.
This is a legal, it is allowed.
You can hack the format as much as you want.
A slide is a....
We don't use slides anymore, the whole notion
of slides is a kind of ridiculous,
So hack it to tell your story.
The last thing:
if you are working with four, five minutes of time
you can rehearse and practice ten times in an hour.
Now I recommend you do it at least once
before you make any slides at all.
Just so that you can figure out what your points are,
what you wanna say.
And as you practice you build the material
and back fill it in.
So to sum up, all of you have a story to tell,
and you are good at it.
Second, don't worry about the Grim Reaper,
you can hack around that.
And third, practice is everything.
And I hope to see you guys, up here, next time.
Thank you.