maggie everyone well that's a great to
have a invented a ten-day set of at your
house the night and i a m last major on
today
corrected
accel and
i mean it's a date because i've got a
call from t_v_ last week she invited me
to be here today so i'm hosting busy
today
so i'm not always wanted to and succumb
to date nights and see
like this evening as part of a really
wanna see d
mysterious people let you guys and i'm
the mysterious ideas you got for us
so um...
before i get my talk i would like to
remind all of you that we are very
special because we all are and five p
where not only the at the we have m_i_t_
because each opposes
most important person epithets
one of their most important person as
because uh... each of us has a magnified
in hand so
and even some of us have more so i a m
the magnifiers enables us to uh...
seeking think very detailed and very
curious about
everything on this planet
celeron
weeknight urs have very curious to know
we have the night at magnifier
and then we are looking for a new ideas
in this year
and then so
so
and so when we had the magnifier we look
for ideas so weak matters have
passionate supreme your ideas and then
once the new ideas recreate something
new ourselves
so
we were hungry for something and then we
get for thank just and then we create
something you are
so retailers have very
we have a lot of innovations and then we
have new ideas and then
once we have those in hands we are
passionate to share
so
passing makes is very important person
so and so what you guys you fall in
tickets hot at ignites happy like to
make
and then so
no even into a hard time tonight in
deeply and i commend with volunteer
again the next experience
so i like to remind all of you that
places like this little green belt where
all m_i_t_ it matters
and then sell maybe uh... so what is the
difference what are the differences
between we did not his and
teddy bears from texas
so tak well since we are we both get
free talks to the world so
one meets the biggest difference the
entertainers is that uh...
is that um... we ourselves
a big difference because not only by
some
remarkable people to talk and the like
defeated in the world class
well here at nights i'm nothing with
small class time
ignite allows anyone who hasn't idea
tata
so
that's the teddy bear and witness
professor tough
so uh... i think the second difference
that makes this different as p m
the language as the years
so um...
issue of caroline in your life she
contact event the instantaneous buffet
in english they only have spent for
other languages but
mostly they use interest
but here we are all fairy tale lucky
because in ignites heavy here we have
them
bug interest in chinese
so it is ferry create that we can
actually there is something else you
different languages that's very frankly
and so and the last day of friends
inputting anne's
with b
format sas we all know
aid tax teddy bear as allowed to speak
for eighteen minutes and it's quite
stunning too because they have to
manually controlled his life and then
so i had nothing for the audience at the
same time fact here at night we found
out that we have
twenty slides
fifteen-second out anthony slide and
then in total it adds up to you on the
five minutes so industrial in five
minutes
a concert but we still do you make a
difference in the world
so for example here
map of my cock
analogy here at the sixteen th
like sewing is nothing too much to go so
i a m
and by the way has another trick i can't
eat you guys to if you really have
enough to stay
and fifteen seconds is not enough for
you
soon this year
and then you copy and paste
several you make this thing al you make
the same flight i've hyphen and so as
you can see
this map is staying here
for let alone surface electric
so am these are the parts hopping to
have today so we have drake's decreased
introduces us to introduces arts
but senators
travel and finally drinks
so and this is your first again talk
tonight and
now it's starting to come on stage in my
tennis
and remember we all have to have fun
tonight paint chip