Good evening everyone, my name is Shanni B,
I'm an English teacher by day,
a Chinese student by afternoon,
but I'm also something like Clark Kent, I have an alterego.
At night I become FireFaye,
professional fire spinner,
fire eater and fire breather.
So you may think I'm a dragon,
or you may think I'm insane,
but today I hope you'll think about a question:
can art turn the world on its head?
Now, my medium of choice is flame artistry,
which has accrued something of a bad name in Taiwan.
So before I convince you that fire dance
can be used for a greater good
I need to dispell a few myths.
If you are a new arrival in this country,
you may not be familiar with the recent accident in Taichung.
In March of this year, a dancer was performing
a fire show at the AHA nightclub
Mid-set he threw a sparkler at the ceiling
which caught the styrofoam soundproofing on fire,
and engulfed the entire building
in a devastating three minutes.
Now the public has long been misinformed about fire dance
and like so many things, they were able to take
an isolated, headline-grabbing incident
as proof for their long held misconceptions.
I don't you to think for a second,
that I'm downplaying this catastrophe
I speak for the firespinning community as a whole
when I say it broke our hearts.
But one million people die from vehicular accidents every year.
Does this necessitate a blanket ban on driving?
Certainly not. If we are sobering aware,
roads can be made safer.
The dancer in question that night was
very new to fire dance.
He had no business performing a public show
with his lack of experience.
Furthermore, the bar itself had previously
been shut down for failing a safety inspection
Not even the most esteemed dancer
in the world could have performed there.
Fire dance is actually quite safe provided
you respect what you're doing
and follow well established safety guidelines,
which I don't have time to outline here.
So if any of these photos have inspired you
to stick flaming objects down your mouth,
please, talk to me first.
Well, time is short, so hopefully by now
I have you at least semi-convinced,
fire dance is not an inherently dangerous and sadistic activity.
Assuming this premise,
I digress back to my original question:
"Can art turn the world on its head?"
and i hope to convince you in the remaining
two minutes that the answer is yes.
In addition to flame arts, I studied ecology
and I'm something of a tree hugger.
So one day I got to thinking:
How can fire dance be used to contribute
towards solutions to ecological problems?
To make a long story short here's some things we've done.
One of my tropes for shows was a benefit
for critically endangered Taiwan sousa dolphins.
In addition to raising forty-five hundred dollars for this cause
we raised awareness by distributing literature and
giving short talks on habitat degradation between sets.
And a few months ago I performed on a
Taiwanese television show
I used the opportunity to introduce a
local NGO, The Society of Wilderness,
and when I won a ten thousand NTD prize,
I donated it to this organization.
So by now you are probably thinking,
"Sure, Shanni, you are well intentioned, but 500 US?
That is a ripple in an ocean, when
measured agains the five hundred million,
Big Oil spends on lobby every year.
You're not gonna save the world this way, wake up."
And I'll tell you, you're right, I'm not,
and that is precisely why I've come here today:
to convince all of you to join me.
Because what if everyone who'd every said:
"I'd love to help, but what can I do?
The problems are so big and I'm so small."
dared to try?
Our ripples could become a tidal wave.
And maybe now you tell me,
"well, I see the logic, but fire freaks me out, man!"
and I'd say, that's okay. Art comes in many forms.
My topic today was inspired by photographer JR,
who pasted giant pictures of Palestinians
and Israelis on the Gaza security strip
to get these warring nations each other as more than enemies.
And one of my personal heroes, John Lennon
inspired generations with the simple words:
Give peace a chance.
Maybe now you'll tell me: "well I'm no iconic rock star"
and I say it again, that matters not.
The global problems we face today are magnificent in scale.
Any solution we find will be multi-stakeholder.
Everyone in this room is good at something.
Maybe you're surfer, you're a wave artist.
Maybe you have a talent with worlds, you're language artist
Maybe you're good at math, for what greater prose exists
than the poetry of nature expressed through numbers.
But maybe you're just a sandwich artist working at Subway.
Whatever it is you do can be used
for something greater than itself.
All it takes is a little creativity, and a little more drive.
Thank you. No go turn the world on its head.